PROFILE

Software Engineer passionate about full-stack web development and problem solving. Served almost 5 years in the United States Marine Corps which reinforced valuable qualities like integrity, communication, initiative, time management, and leadership. I have a strong work ethic and personal/professional growth is important to me.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full-Time, Software Development Bootcamp

KENNESAW STATE UNIVERSITY

Computer Science 2016-2017

NSS PROJECTS

Level Up

I designed Level Up as not only a workout organizer, but also a data visualization tool. For anyone that wants to take more of a scientific approach to working out, a user can record their workout data and see a graph of their results in various formats over one to six months. It was designed as a mobile web application so users can easily record data using their phone. This is a frontend application built in **React** and uses **JSON**Server for data storage.

github.com/chase-fite/level-up

SupplyMate

Based off of a previous job in logistics, working for a small quarry drilling company. I wanted to create an inventory and supply request web application to simplify and streamline their logistics process. SupplyMate allows logistics and remote employees to easily coordinate supply deliveries. This is a full stack web application built using SQLite, Python, Django REST, JavaScript, and React. github.com/chase-fite/supplymate-client github.com/chase-fite/supplymate-api

CONTACT

Cell:: 770-355-3739

E-mail: chasef7031@gmail.com Portfolio: chase-fite.github.io

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/chase-fite/ Github: github.com/chase-fite

CHASE FITE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

WORK EXPERIENCE

TUCKER CONNELLY CONSULTING

Junior Software Engineer | July 2020 to August 2020

- Refactored Node.js, Puppeteer web scraping scripts to be more modular and match database changes
- Debugged and implemented fixes for failed scraping jobs
- · Improved testing with Jest by adding a variety of mock data
- Utilized Rambler and Postico for PostgreSQL database table changes

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Teaching Assistant | April 2020 to June 2020

- Assisted with a remote, 3 month, Python / Django back-end class
- Participated in guided discussions and lead class lectures when needed
- Guided students towards code solutions
- · Testing technology prior to projects or demonstrations

Apprentice Software Developer | Sep. 2019 to April 2020

Intensive full-time 6 month software development bootcamp focused on cultivating full-stack developers who are able to work effectively and independently in a collaborative environment.

- GitHub for version control and to enable group collaboration; project management tracking with Github Projects
- Object Oriented Programming with DRY, modular, commented, and readable code
- Project planning using wireframes and entity relationship diagrams
- Built dynamic, single page web applications with React, JavaScript and HTML
- Backend development of Django REST API
- Queried JSON Server and used SQL and Django ORM to query a SQLite database
- Styling CSS frameworks Bootstrap and Tachyons
- Developed a full-stack application with Django REST API, a SQLite database, and React front-end

QUARRY SERVICES

Logistics Specialist | Sep. 2018 to June 2019

- Focused on warehouse organization to improve supply chain efficiency and save money through cataloging excess drill parts
- Coordinated with drillers, mechanics, and managers for deliveries, maintenance, and driller assistance to meet company goals and deadlines
- Consistently assembled accurate supply requests and delivered to quarries across the Southeast U.S. in a timely manner